<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[iBumble]]></title>
  <link href="http://ibumble.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ibumble.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-06T13:12:10+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://ibumble.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chintan Patel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, World! (Again)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/02/02/first-post-on-the-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T23:44:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/02/02/first-post-on-the-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After spending a week learning Jekyll/Octopress/GitHub Pages, I am finally able to start <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html">blogging like a hacker</a>.</p>

<p>Being an iOS Developer, getting the hang of blogging with <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> took some time but i highly recommend it for any developer who wants to escape the security updates of WordPress or if you are just looking for an adventure. I also had the added advantage of not having any previous blog posts to migrate but even if you have a blog already, there are <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Blog-Migrations">migration steps</a> available for almost every blog engine out there like WordPress, Movable Type, Posterous, Tumblr, Blogger (Blogspot) etc. and the list still goes on.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After playing around with Jekyll and <a href="http://jekyllbootstrap.com/">Jekyll Bootstrap</a> for a few days, i soon realized it will be a waste of time trying to set up a blog with a responsive theme all by myself due to my limited web development skills. It was at this point that i discovered <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which felt like it was designed especially for people like me who are developers but not necessarily web developers and after i found out <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/">Matt Gemmell</a> too uses Octopress to host his blog with the default theme, the path ahead for me was clear.</p>

<p>I do have a HostGator shared hosting account but looking at the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites">sheer number of blogs</a> hosted from GitHub, i decided to try out hosting the blog on <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>. Since hosting on GitHub Pages is free, now my blog only costs the domain renewal fees (10-15 USD/year) and not hosting + domain renewal fees (~120 USD / year). Money staying in the bank is always a good thing. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
