<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[iBumble]]></title>
  <link href="http://ibumble.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ibumble.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-09-14T02:26:54+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://ibumble.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chintan Patel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Image to PDF Converter App for iOS: How to Create a PDF From Multiple Images on iPhone and iPad]]></title>
    <link href="http://ibumble.com/blog/2015/10/23/image-to-pdf-converter-app-for-ios-how-to-create-a-pdf-from-multiple-images-on-iphone-and-ipad/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-23T15:54:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://ibumble.com/blog/2015/10/23/image-to-pdf-converter-app-for-ios-how-to-create-a-pdf-from-multiple-images-on-iphone-and-ipad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>App Store link: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/image-to-pdf-converter-pro/id758170890?at=1l3uZR4&amp;ct=pdfbp">Image To PDF Converter</a></p>

<p>While dealing with the problem of sending business expense reports or bills to Finance department while working as an employee in a company, I was often faced with the task of sending bills to Finance department as a proof to claim reimbursement.</p>

<p>To fulfill this task, just capturing pictures from phone camera and sending captured images of bills as separate email attachments or zipping them together might cause some file management pain if the number of images increase.</p>

<p>To deal with this, I decided to come up with an iOS app&hellip;<!-- more --> which creates a PDF from multiple selected images. This app allows the user to select multiple images from Photo Library and reorder them as needed. You can also delete selected images from the list if you wish. After you are satisfied with the ordering, you just have to press &ldquo;Create PDF&rdquo; button which will instantly generate a PDF with each image printed on a separate PDF page.</p>

<p> When the PDF is generated, the app shows all sharing options like &ldquo;Printing PDF&rdquo;, &ldquo;Upload to Dropbox&rdquo;, &ldquo;Upload to Google Drive&rdquo;, &ldquo;Upload to Microsoft OneDrive&rdquo;, &ldquo;Mail&rdquo;, etc and you can also open any other PDF editor on your iPhone or iPad to edit newly created PDF. Moreover, the app is a Universal app which means you just have to buy the app once and it will run great on both iPhone and iPad.</p>

<p> Hope you all enjoy my app! App Store link: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/image-to-pdf-converter-pro/id758170890?at=1l3uZR4&amp;ct=pdfbp">Image To PDF Converter</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Open winmail.dat Files on iOS (iPhone and iPad)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/11/13/how-to-open-winmail-dot-dat-files-on-ios-iphone-and-ipad/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-13T15:15:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/11/13/how-to-open-winmail-dot-dat-files-on-ios-iphone-and-ipad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A week ago, i released my first iOS app to the App Store: <a href="http://taps.io/winmail">Winmail.dat File Viewer Pro</a>. This post is about how I did market research to find what to build as my first iOS app on App Store.</p>

<p>If Microsoft Outlook server is not configured correctly, it can send out emails as &ldquo;winmail.dat&rdquo; files instead of the actual email with attachments.</p>

<!--more -->


<p>The winmail.dat file is a TNEF-encoded file containing the email body text as a &ldquo;.rtf&rdquo; file along with any other attachments if present.</p>

<p>Receiving such files on any platform can be a problem because the recipient is not sure how to open the winmail.dat file to access text and attachments contained within the email. Moreover, most senders will be unaware of the cause of this issue and may need help of their IT department to solve the issue.</p>

<p>Some users on <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/search.jspa?&amp;q=winmail.dat">Apple forums</a> are also suggesting that this issue has started occurring more frequently after they updated to iOS 7 but i have not been able to find any such direct correlation.</p>

<p>Microsoft (or Apple) do not seem to be keen on providing a solution to this years-old problem which would allow users to view contents of TNEF-encoded winmail.dat files without using any 3rd party software.</p>

<p>I saw this as a niche iOS app opportunity and just the kind of weekend project which was perfect for me to release as my first iOS app in the App Store after about 20+ apps shipped to various clients over nearly 5 years as a full-time iOS Developer.</p>

<p>This app may not be useful to everyone but it is inevitable for anyone who receives one of these dreaded winmail.dat email attachments on their iPhone or iPad and have no idea what to do with it. Now, by using <a href="http://taps.io/winmail">Winmail.dat File Viewer Pro</a>, you will be able to open winmail.dat attachments on your iOS device with ease. You can also save the attached files to your Dropbox, Google Drive, Photo Gallery or share it with others using email, Facebook, Twitter etc. depending on the file type.</p>

<p>Since this app is already live on the app store since about 7 days, i will be doing another post this weekend sharing sales/downloads data and thoughts about pricing and designing the app.</p>

<p>So there goes the first app of my own in App Store after thousands of hours of client work!</p>

<p>App Store link: <a href="http://taps.io/winmail">Winmail.dat File Viewer Pro</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello, World! (Again)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/02/02/first-post-on-the-new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T23:44:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://ibumble.com/blog/2013/02/02/first-post-on-the-new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After spending a week learning Jekyll/Octopress/GitHub Pages, I am finally able to start <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html">blogging like a hacker</a>.</p>

<p>Being an iOS Developer, getting the hang of blogging with <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> took some time but i highly recommend it for any developer who wants to escape the security updates of WordPress or if you are just looking for an adventure. I also had the added advantage of not having any previous blog posts to migrate but even if you have a blog already, there are <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Blog-Migrations">migration steps</a> available for almost every blog engine out there like WordPress, Movable Type, Posterous, Tumblr, Blogger (Blogspot) etc. and the list still goes on.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After playing around with Jekyll and <a href="http://jekyllbootstrap.com/">Jekyll Bootstrap</a> for a few days, i soon realized it will be a waste of time trying to set up a blog with a responsive theme all by myself due to my limited web development skills. It was at this point that i discovered <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> which felt like it was designed especially for people like me who are developers but not necessarily web developers and after i found out <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/">Matt Gemmell</a> too uses Octopress to host his blog with the default theme, the path ahead for me was clear.</p>

<p>I do have a HostGator shared hosting account but looking at the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites">sheer number of blogs</a> hosted from GitHub, i decided to try out hosting the blog on <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>. Since hosting on GitHub Pages is free, now my blog only costs the domain renewal fees (10-15 USD/year) and not hosting + domain renewal fees (~120 USD / year). Money staying in the bank is always a good thing. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
